油炸虾，龙虾，从未吃过龙虾
Deep fried shrimp, and lobster.Never had lobster.
是煮还是烤?怎么做好吃?
What, do you boil 'em or grill 'em?Which one's better?
都做好了
Ah, just get 'em both.
然后我知道我需要草莓麦芽,
And I know I need a strawberry malt,
然后有没有盒装的巧克力甜麦圈?
and then there's those,chocolate donuts that come in a box?
我们会尽力供应的
We'll do our best to accommodate.
明天会把你转到等待室
Tomorrow you'll be moved to a holding cell.
你就在那吃你的最后一餐
That's where you'll get your last meal.
你还会有宪法赋予的由你选择的,精神导师会见
You also have a constitutional right to,the spiritual advisor of your choice.
不，我不需要
Naw, I don't need none of that.
最后一件要想的事:
One last thing to think about:
在我读完死刑核准书后,
After I read the execution warrant,
你会有机会发表声明
you'll be given an opportunity,to make a statement.
你也许需要时间,考虑一下你的最后遗言是什么
You might want to take some time,and think about what you want,to say as your final words.
你，克拉伦! 你听见了吗?由我选择的精神导师
Yo, Clarence! You hear that?A spiritual advisor of my choice! He-he.
别麻烦了，反正你是要下地狱的
Don't matter, you goin' to hell anyway.
你觉得我会再得到一次滞留吗?
You think I'll get another stay?
你会的，最高法院认为处决,智障人士不对
You should. Supreme Court say it ain't right to kill retards.
别聊了，锻炼时间到
Cut the chatter! Exercise time.
一小时后回来，好好享受吧
Be back in an hour. Enjoy.
你干嘛打我那么多次, 克拉伦?
Why did you hit me so many times, Clarence?
你知道为什么
You know why!
你本该停止
You could have stopped.
你刺了我的后背
You stabbed me in the back, man.
- 我没有...- 你打的不公平
- I never st...- You couldn't fight fair.
就象你吗?
Like you did?
我有妻子和三个孩子
I had a wife and three kids.
你是个混蛋疯子,开门，开门
You are a sick bastard!,Open the door! Open the door!
嘿，我曾那样对待你吗，老兄?
Hey! What'd I ever do to you, man?
你不能进去
You can't go in there.
你是谁，而且干嘛带领带?
Who are you, and,why are you wearing a tie?
我是卡蒂医生的新助手,我可以替你通报吗？
I'm Dr. Cuddy's new assistant.Can I tell her what it's regarding?
是，我想知道
Yes. I would like to know,why she gets a secretary and I don't.
我是她的助手，不是她的秘书,我是从Rutgers毕业的
I'm her assistant, not her secretary.I graduated from Rutgers.
嗯，我不知道他们有秘书学校
Hmm. I didn't know,they had a secretarial school.
嗯，我希望你曾接受过有关,性骚扰方面的法律课
Well, I hope you took some classes,in sexual harassment law.
''ka-ching''这个字对你有意义吗？,我要进去了
Does the word ''ka-ching'',mean anything to you? I'm going in now.
豪斯医生，我们在开会
Dr. House, we are in the middle of a meeting.
干嘛雇个男秘书？,JDate不称职吗？
What's with hiring a male secretary?JDate not working out?
他挺可爱，小心点
He is cute. Be careful.
她不象你，无法走进酒吧20分钟,就找到灵魂伴侣
She's not like you.She can't just walk into a bar and,pick up her soul mate in twenty minutes.
我跟马克在一个募捐会遇上的，结果……
I met Mark at a fundraiser,that happened to be held at a...
你跟我是在一个脱衣舞俱乐部认识的
You met me at a strip club.
你是我花的最不值的20块钱
You were the worst,two dollars I ever spent.
我们回头见
We'll catch up later.
史戴西，是豪斯，我知道你能应付
Stacy, it's House.I know you can handle it.
没什么好应付的，显然他想跟你单谈
Nothing to handle. It's obvious,he wants to talk to you alone.
如果你跟史戴西一起工作有问题,你该早说
If you have a problem working,with Stacy you should have said so.
我能干什么?
What was I supposed to do?
让她走？那很粗鲁
Ask her to leave?That's just rude.
死囚，我要那个病例
Death row guy.I want the case.
你怎么知道的?
How do you even know about him?
你没有医院主机的准入
You don't have access,to the hospital's mainframe.
对，可“舞裤”有
No, but ''partypants'' does.
你偷我的密码?
You stole my password?
不能算是偷，因为过于显而易见了
Hardly counts as stealing;,it's a pretty obvious choice.
我把死囚病例给了努洛医生
Well, I have already assigned,Death Row Guy to Dr. Nolo.
努洛？我不想说其他医生的坏话
Nolo? Well, I don't want to say,anything bad about another doctor,
尤其是个没用的醉鬼...
especially a useless drunk...
你止疼药成瘾
You are addicted to pain pills.
但我不是没用，告诉努洛医生我接手了
But I'm not useless.Tell Nolo I'm talking over.
努洛医生是合格的心脏病专家
Dr. Nolo is a board certified cardiologist.
哦，好啊，我肯定他会罗列普遍病因来解释,为什么这个家伙的心脏只泵气不泵血
Oh, good. I'm sure he'll explore all the usual,options for why a guy's heart starts beating,so fast it pumps out air instead of blood.
等等，没有普遍病因
Wait a second...there are no usual options!
你有多想要这个病例?
How badly do you want this?
这周我多给你两小时的出诊时间
I will give you,two more clinic hours this week.
别太卖力了
Don't bend over for the soap.
只是心脏，还是病人有其他抱怨?
Cameron: Just the heart, or,the patient have any other complaints?
病人不跟任何人说话
The patient's not talking to anybody.
我们去哪?
Where are we going?
你出两小时的诊
You are going to,the clinic for two hours.
我？为什么？
Me? Why?
跟卡蒂说去吧
Talk to Cuddy.
她让我去Mercer州立监狱的死牢，,我不知道
She's got me going to,Mercer State Prison,Capital Sentences unit, I don't know.
没有浪费我们时间更好的途径了吗？
Aren't there better ways,to spend our time?
问题不错
Good question.
什么能让人得其所哉?
What makes a person deserving?
杀妻的人比骗妻是人更该死吗?
Is a man who cheats on his wife,more deserving than,a man who kills his wife?
嗯，是，对啊
Uh... yeah. Actually, he is.
娈童癖的人呢?
What about a child molester?
肯定不是好人，可他没杀人啊
Certainly not a good guy,but he didn't kill anybody.
或许可以给抗生素，但不给核磁共振,你说呢?
Maybe he can get antibiotics,but no MRIs. What about you?
你拒绝给偷车贼什么医疗救助?
What medical care should you,be denied for being a car thief?
回来我检查
I'll review it when I get back.
你的病人第一个月捅了一个人,折断了另一个的脖子
Your patient shanked,one inmate his first month here,broke another one's neck,
差点砍掉了我警卫的头...
nearly decapitated one of my guards...
放心，我的医疗态度不错
Relax, I've got a great bedside manner.
把他安置在医务所太危险了
Too dangerous to,house him in the infirmary.
你不用担心，我们作足了防范
You don't have to worry,we've taken every precaution.
我让我手下清除了牢房里所有的,钢笔、曲别针和订书机
I've had my men clear from the cell,all pens, paperclips and staplers.
任何可作为武器的物品
Any supplies that,might be used as a weapon.
打开
Open her up!
因你的来访，我们给他上了手铐脚镣
For your visit,we've got him cuffed and shackled.
更别提，你还在这里
And  yet, you're staying out there.
哦，你得给我那个
Uhp! You're going to,have to give me that.
不想让任何人受伤
Wouldn't want anybody to get hurt.
- 嗨,- 我是卡麦伦医生
- Hi. - Hi.- I'm Dr. Cameron.
你觉得怎样？
How're you feeling?
嗯，有点咳嗽，没什么
Eh. Little cough, no big deal.
好吧，那你在这干嘛?
Okay, then.What're you doing here?
我刚在大学找了工作,他们需要健康保证
I just got a job at the university.They need a health clearance.
显然我有点贫血,他们要我再检查
Apparently I'm a little anemic,so they made me get some more tests.
- 家族病史有贫血吗?- 据我所知，没有
- Any family history of anemia?- Not that I know of.
我小时候妈妈得癌死了,前些年爸爸心脏衰竭
My  mom died of cancer,when I was a kid, my dad's heart,gave out a couple of years ago.
兄弟姐妹?
Brothers and sisters?
我看家族病史很短，我就一个
I'm afraid it's a short,family history. That's it.
我曾有丈夫，但，不成功
I had a husband once,but... didn't stick.
我的检查回来了，可能在那个病例里
My tests should be back,probably in that file.
也许
Probably.
没事吗?
Is everything okay?
你又做X光了吗?
Wilson:,Did you redo the x-ray?
两次
Twice.
你不需要我督导
Well, you don't need a consult.
你知道诊断
You know the diagnosis.
她不过是咳嗽而已
All she has is a cough.
指甲和嘴唇青紫，他缺氧
Bluish tinge to the fingernails,lips... he's hypoxic.
什么意思?
What's that mean?
他氧气不足
He's not getting enough oxygen.
你知道人们都说人没爱不能活?
You know how people say,you can't live without love?
氧气比那还重要
Well, oxygen's,even more important.
他肺部有积水，呼吸频率50...
He's got fluid in his lungs,breathing rate of 50...
他需要插肺管接呼吸机
he needs to be intubated,and put on a respirator.
没有呼吸机
Don't have a respirator.
一小时内接上，不然他死定了
Better get one in about an hour,or you're gonna lose him.
我会写申请的
I'll make out a requisition.
州政府已核准了他的死刑
The state's already,sentenced this man to die.
我觉得州政府会在意他的死法
I think the state was,a tad more specific about ''how''.
这是豪斯医生
[on the phone],This is Dr. Gregory House.
我需要一辆到Mercer州立监狱的救护车
I need an ambulance to pick-up,at Mercer State Prison.
没用的电话,我的人会在大门拦住他们
Wasted call, my men,will stop them at the gate.
一个死囚休想离开我的监狱
No way a Death Row inmate,leaves my prison,
至少不是从前门
least not through the front doors.
你干的挺快
You work fast.
你也是
So do you.
- 奇怪吗?- 对
- Is that a shock?- Yeah.
容易，我曾说服我的职员找马法官
It was easy.Once I convinced the clerk,to take it to Judge Markem,
她是8项改善议案的受骗者
she's a sucker for,Eight Amendment arguments.
别说了，我都有点兴奋了
Stop, I'm getting turned on.
豪斯
House!
只是顾问一下?
Ruh-row!
你指望我们为这家伙关闭正层楼么?
You expect us to shut down,an entire floor for this guy?
你做头了吗?
Did you do something to your hair?
史戴西?
Stacy?
你说你已经搞定她了...
You said you cleared with her...
拜托，你认识我多久了,还搞不清我什么时候在搞笑?
Come on. You've known me,how long and still you can't tell,when I'm joshin' ya?
把他送回监狱，现在
Take him back to prison. Now.
不行，讽刺的说，我现在已经被,你律师申请的法庭令给绑住了
No, can't. Ironically,I'm bound by this court order,which your ace attorney got.
我希望在把他运回去受死前,使他有好转
I have to make him all better,before shipping him back,for the state to kill him.
是我的原因，还是就是很怪异？
Is it just me,or is that weird?
无论如何，我们走路了
Anyway, we're walking.
有人把这个放我椅子上了
Somebody left this on my chair.
很聪明，因为这强迫我要么看病例,要么永远也别坐下
It's clever. 'Cause it forces me,to either deal with the file,or never sit down again.
柯辛蒂，我跟他说你会见她
Cindy Kramer.I told her you'd see her.
你不该那么告诉她
You shouldn't have told her that.
她得来硬鳞片细胞肺癌，顶多活6个月
She's got metastatic squamous,cell lung cancer, six months, tops.
你都不看x光片吗?
Have you even looked at the x-ray?
不，乱猜的，一个新游戏
No, just guessing.It's a new game.
如果错了，她就是个填充熊
If it's wrong,she gets a stuffed bear.
X光片上的一点污迹并不非得是晚期啊
A spot on a x-ray doesn't,necessarily mean that she's terminal.
我爱孩子，如此充满希望
I love children.So filled with hope.
可能是肺炎，可能是增生
It could be pneumonia.It could be sarcodosis.
如果不是她的另一个肺,有淋巴节肿大，可能
Could be, if she didn't already have,swollen hilar lymph nodes,on the other lung.
难道我们不能,集体讨论另一个方案吗?
Could we at least,brainstorm for other ideas?
谢谢你
Thank you.
我仍希望是肺炎、增生
I still think it could be,pneumonia and sarcodosis,
但也需要排除肺结核
but we should,check for tuberculosis
也要排除心脏充血失败的可能
and definitely rule out,congestive heart failure.
五个死亡步骤
The five stages of dying.
没错，我个人会认为这是年幼者的废话
Exactly. Personally, I think,it's all just new-age crap,
但见你热泪盈眶,小狗般无辜眼神
but from your tear-filled,puppy-dog eyes
我觉得我已经说的够了
I think I've made my point.
现在去告诉辛蒂，不管她叫什么,她快死了
Now go tell Cindy,Whatever-her-name-is that she's dying.
心动过速，肺水肿，疑似？
Tachycardia,pulmonary edema, likely suspects?
死囚?
The Death Row guy?
你替代辛蒂病例的就是这个?
That's who you're working on,instead of Cindy?
上帝，我得学着不随便动粗
God, I've got to learn,not to beat around the bush.
说到死，我的意思是无论我们做什么
By dying, I mean,no matter what we do.
很快，她就会死
Very, very soon,she is going to be dead.
还不够清楚吗?
Is it still to subtle?
我发过誓不伤害
I took an oath to do no harm.
对，可不是有人逼你签的
Yeah, well, it's not like,they make you sign it or anything.
我们治好你的病人，他回去接受死刑
We cure your patient,he goes back to Death Row.
他回去死牢，他们要杀他
He goes back to,Death Row, they kill him!
他呆在这，我们不给他治,他死了
He stays here and,we don't treat him, he dies,
我还是不给辛蒂什么的治
and I still don't treat,Cindy Lou-Who.
我们可以继续这个了吗?
Can we get on with this?
行，我就知道我能指望上你的支持
Yeah, I knew I could count,on your help for your homie.
没错，我是黑人
Exactly, I'm black.
我同情由男人带大的城里人
I sympathize for guys,who grew up in the city,kept down by the man.
有道理
Makes sense to me.
都是废话,你不能因为自己杀人就怨社会
It's a bunch of crap.You can't blame society for the fact,that you chose to become a killer.
那家伙可能是海洛因成瘾,导致心动过速和肺水肿
The  guy's probably a heroin addict,which explains the tachycardia,which caused the pulmonary edema.
一个死囚怎么能搞到海洛因?
How does an inmate on Death Row,get his hands on heroin?
你说真的吗?
Are you serious?
这人了解监狱
The man knows prisons.
等我们有游艇问题时会找你的
When we've got a yachting question, we'll come to you.
好，毒品，检验他的头发,血液，尿，操作
Okay, drugs it is. Test his hair,blood, and urine, the works.
谢谢你们的支持
Thanks for getting my back.
我以为你们这些神学院的小子反对死刑呢
I thought you seminary boys,were against the death penalty.
我离开神学院了
I left the seminary.
以反对他们的最高刑罚?
Over their stance,on capital punishment?
理论上我反对死刑
I'm against,the death penalty in principle.
但实际上，看杀人犯被处决给我带来的困扰,比我老板给我的要少
In practice, however,watching a murder die causes me,a lot less grief than annoying my boss.
你们进去前我们要检查
Guard: We gotta,check you out before you go in.
司法部的调查证实量刑有人种依据
Department of Justice statistics,show that it's a racially,motivated form of punishment.
黑人被判死刑的几率比白人高10倍
Black defendants are,ten times more likely to get,a death sentence than whites.
那也不表示我们就得放弃死刑，对吧?
Doesn't mean we need to,get rid of the death penalty, do we?
我们只需要多杀白人就是了
It just means we need,to kill more white people.
没事的，你在医院,我们在照顾你
It's okay, you're in a hospital,we're taking care of you.
冷静，你将被注射两毫克的Atvan
Chase:,Stay calm, you're gonna be...push two milligrams Atvan!
水……
Water... water.
口渴的细分是什么？
What's the differential,for being thirsty?
他有点脱水和失神
He was just a little dehydrated,and out of his mind.
我们给他吊了盐水，现在没事了
We upped his saline drip,he's fine now.
血，尿检验结果返回没问题，,系统无鸦片痕迹
Blood and urine tests came back clean,no sign of opiates in his system.
别那样做
Don't do that.
怎么你有解释躯体,毒物反应阴性的豪斯理论吗?
What, you have some,House theory explaining,heroin use despite a negative test?
没
Nope.
只是该是我往板上写
Only I get to write on the board.
那么不是毒品
So it's not drugs.
还有什么能导致心脏跑风?
What else can cause,the heart to do wind sprints?
血样检测返回了，有...
Got the blood work back, any...
不正常吗?
...thing out of the ordinary?
他的bi-carb低
His bi-carb is low.
对，但是哪一柱?
Yeah, but which column?
是心动过速的结果还是成因？
Could be the result of the tachycardia,could be the cause?
是成因
It's the cause.
为什么，因为你希望如此?
Why, because you want it to be?
让我们看看这个对你,另一个病人有什么帮助？
Let's see how well that works,with your other patient.
我们在玩文字游戏
We're just talking semantics here.
我们该给他吊水然后送回去
We should put him,on a bi-carb drip and send him back.
对，给他记数
Right, buff his numbers.
不必担心深层理由
Don't bother trying to,figure out the underlying cause.
我以为你关心病人
I thought you cared about patients.
我们的工作不是确保他能抱孙子
Foreman:,Our job isn't to make sure,he can bounce his grandkids on his lap,
只是让他健康地回去受死
our job is to get him healthy enough,to go back to Death Row.
我们是要给他诊断
Our job is to diagnose him.
怎么了?
What?
妈妈和爸爸吵架,不等于我们不再爱你们了
Mommy and Daddy are having a little fight,it doesn't mean we stop loving you.
现在，出去表演吧
Now, go outside and play.
给爸爸拿烟和血液雾化检验结果回来
Get Daddy some smokes,and an arterial blood gas test.
哇，真有进步
Wow. That was impressive.
好吧，我现在想的是什么数字?
Okay, what number am I thinking of?
你是想害我丢饭碗吗?
Were you trying to get me fired?
如果你不想让我在这工作,干嘛不直说呢?
If you didn't want me working here,why didn't you just say so?
我只是不想你在这工作，我的办公室
I just don't want you,working here, in my office.
楼里其他地方没事
But anywhere else,in the building is fine.
- 这是个大医院,- 我是律师，你是混蛋
- It's a big hospital.- I'm a lawyer. You're a jerk.
彼此重叠
There's gonna to be some overlap.
上帝，我希望那是个委婉的说法
God, I hope that was a euphemism.
小地方让我不爽
Cuddy just reamed me.
- 我希望能懂你意思,- 信任你
- I hope that one means,what I think it means.- For trusting you!
她雇我时觉得她至少,找了个你不会上下其手的人
She figured when she hired me,she'd at least have someone,you couldn't walk all over.
顺便说，数字是6
The number was six,by the way.
我需要知道，我是否可以信任你?
I need to know,can I trust you?
如果我不就卡蒂的事撒谎
If I hadn't lied to you,about Cuddy's approval,
我的病人会死
my patient would be dead.
太棒了
Great.
现在我了解了,现在我们可以在一起工作了
Now I know.Now we can work together.
我要从你的股动脉抽一些血
I'm drawing some blood,from your femoral artery.
- 我的什么?- 经过你的腹股沟
- From my what?- Runs through your groin.
你以为你就拿那个戳进我的宝贝里吗?
You think you're gonna stick me,in the jewels with that?
非常靠近你的大腿
It's really closer to your thigh.
从技术上说，你的宝贝其实是个展示品
Technically, at this point,it seems like your jewels are,more for display purposes, anyway.
等等，给我点止疼药什么的
Hold up, hold up. Give me,some pain killers, or something.
象你这样的厉害角色不需要
Tough guy like you don't need 'em.
算了吧，把我麻翻了吧，伙计
Forget that, numb me up, man.
你有社团纹身?让我看看
You got some gang ink?Let me see that.
是土生美国人标记,意思是“生命的力量”
It's a Native American symbol.It means ''the force of life.''
那就是你告诉这帮白人,让你作医生的理由？
That's what you tell,all these white dudes,so they let you play doctor?
没错，把他们都骗了
Yep. Got 'em all fooled.
说真的，怎么一个象你这样的,黑帮能穿白大褂？
For real, how a brother like you go,from gang-banger to wearing a white coat?
一个象你这样的人又是怎么,把一个爱的女人头骨都凿进去了呢?
How's a guy like you go,from loving a woman,to punching her skull in?
那婊子出轨
Bitch stepped out.
Argh!
很抱歉，看来我用的利多卡因不够
Sorry about that.Guess I didn't use enough lidocaine.
血液雾化指标出来了,pH值7.28，减量HCO3
Blood gas came back with,a pH of 7.28 and decreased HCO3.
可以说明两件事
Which means two things.
最重要的，卡麦伦关于,bi-carb的说法错了
Most importantly,Cameron was wrong about the bi-carb,
稍轻的，我们有新症状了
and less significantly,we have a new symptom.
阴离子酸毒症
Anion gap acidosis.
谁胖? 来啊，,假装喜欢小狗
Who's chubby? Come on,pretend he loves puppies.
假装是人类，你们有什么?
Pretend he's a human being.What've you got?
我觉得要重新考虑毒品
I think we should,reconsider drugs.
已经测试阴性了
He already tested negative.
所以我说重新考虑
That's why I said reconsider.
在少管所，我砍牛至当大麻卖
Back in juvie, I cut up,oregano and sold it as pot.
你就是那么进医学院的吗?
Is that how you put yourself,through med school?
如果卡麦伦说是海洛因，而其实是其他的?
What if Clarence thought,he was taking heroin,but it was something else?
什么其他的能导致酸毒症?
What ''something else'' could,lead to anion gap acidosis?
Mudpiles.
嗯，你不需要申请
Well,  you don't have to ask.
回来前洗手就行了
Just wash your hands,before you come back.
甲醇，尿毒症，糖尿病...
Methanol, uremia, diabetes...
哇，那是记忆术，有道理
Oh, it's a mnemonic.That makes sense, too.
三聚乙醛，乳酸，异烟肼...
Paraldehyde,INH, lactic acid...
- 绕圈,- 异烟肼?
- Rewind.- INH?
没准
Yahtzee!
治肺结核的药
Drugs for tuberculosis.
1/4的监狱人口感染结核病
Nearly a quarter of the prison,populationis infected with TB.
向福满一样的聪明人把症状归入了海洛因
Clever entrepreneur like Foreman here,chops up his meds, passes it off as heroin.
异烟肼中毒可以解释所有症状
INH poisoning would,explain all the symptoms.
谁愿意把脑袋伸到,监狱克拉伦的秘密藏货点去？
Who wants to head over to the prison,and find Clarence's secret stash?
- 好，我来.- 很好，就小蔡吧
- Fine, I'll do it.- Great, Chase it is.
我推测你糟践我是有理由的吧?
I assume you have,a reason beyond wanting to,make me completely miserable?
你的嘴更漂亮
You've got a prettier mouth.
同屋的人会更愿意向你开放
Better chance the inmates,will open up to you.
这男人昏迷了
The man's in a coma.
他不在意
He didn't mind.
- 我问过了,- 你用饭盒压住他了
- I asked.- You're getting crumbs all over him.
你说到底为什么他们,往昏迷病人屋里放电视?
Why do you think they put TVs,in coma patients' rooms, anyway?
有人觉得他们听得见
Some people think,they can still hear.
那就放收音机啊
So leave them a radio.
他的眼睛闭着，谁会觉得他能看见?
His eyes are closed;,who thinks he can see?
你知道为什么人们友善对待他人?
You know why people,are nice to other people?
哦，这个我知道，啊..
Oh, I know this one. Ah...
因为人们好，正直，关怀
Because people are,good, decent and caring.
不是那个，那么人胆小
Either that, or people are cowards.
如果我刻薄对你，你也会刻薄对我
If I'm mean to you,you'll be mean to me.
彼此毁灭
Mutually assured destruction.
没错，你要吃这些薯片吗?
Exactly. You're gonna eat these chips?
你要说重点吗?
You gonna get to your point?
你需要人喜欢你
You need people to like you.
我不在乎别人是否喜欢我
I don't care if people like me.
是，但是你需要人喜欢你,因为你需要人
Yes. But you need people to like you,because you need people.
除非你认为下次你自己办法庭令
Unless you think you can get,the next court order yourself.
如果史戴西不信任你,你就没法用她
If Stacy can't trust you,you can't use her.
甚至是比她甩了她丈夫...
And that's not even dealing,with the greater agenda...
再次爱上你还重要的议程
of getting her to dump her husband,and fall in love with you all over again.
我知道你是她的朋友，但是
I know you're friends with her, but
但是有个暗语是,兄弟重于女人，老兄
there is a code.Bros before hos, man.
- 废物,- 怎么了?
[Pager beeps]
——废话——这是什么?
- Crap.- What is it?
死囚要死了
Death Row guy is dying.
[有哔哔声,来自世界各地]
[There are beeps,coming from all over]
心搏徐缓，心率掉到30,挺不了多久了
Bradycardia. His heart rate's,dropped to 30, it's not going,to hold that much longer.
你是打算就这么拖死他,还是给他阿托品?
Are you just waiting to call time of death,or are you gonna give him atropine?
暂时缓解?
Foreman:,Temporary fix?
对，不管怎样，这些糖尿病,患者都是靠胰岛素过日子的
Right. Anyway, those diabetics,are all hung up on insulin.
再来点无妨
They're just gonna,have to take more.
阿托品只能延长几小时而已
Atropine's only gonna,buy you a few hours!
我们都还不知道这家伙什么问题呢...
We don't even know,what's wrong with this guy...
滚出去
Just get out of here.
[心率开始爬升]
[Heart rate starts to climb]
是小蔡
[on cell],This is Chase.
你已经打出供词了吗?
Did you beat any confessions,out of anybody?
我还没跟任何犯人谈话呢
I haven't spoken to any inmates.
难道没人干正事了吗?
Does anybody do their jobs anymore?
我确认克拉伦的性命不值得我冒险
I've decided Clarence's life,isn't worth risking mine for.
我欣赏你的坦白
I appreciate your candor.
你究竟去没去监狱，,还是在打马球?
Did you even go to the prison,or are you just out playing polo?
我在搜克拉伦的牢房
I'm searching both Clarence's cells.
我猜如果他用什么，那一定藏在牢房
I figure, if he's on something,it's stashed somewhere.
除非他用光了
Unless he finished it.
对，那多可惜阿
Yeah, that'd be a shame.
He could have shoved it anywhere,there's envelopes stacked to the ceiling,bottles of copier toner, boxes of rubber bands,他肯定藏哪里了，天花板的信封,颜料瓶子，橡皮盒子
He could have shoved it anywhere,there's envelopes stacked to the ceiling,bottles of copier toner, boxes of rubber bands
算了，回来吧
Call it off.Come on back.
怎么了?
What's going on?
你快死了
You're dying.
那该喝上最后一杯
That deserves a last drink.
你不错
You're okay.
谢谢，那意义重大
Thanks. That means a lot.
所有测试都无法确诊吗?
All the tests have been inconclusive?
诊断是艺术多于科学的
Diagnostics is more of,an art than a science.
我现在该开始担心了吗?
Should I be worried right now?
我给全国顶尖诊断专家工作
I work for one of the top,diagnosticians in the country.
我们会尽力诊断的
We're pouring all of our,energy into figuring this out.
以为你们这些罪犯知道怎么喝酒
Thought you convicts,knew how to drink.
你至少少喝了三杯
You're at least three shots behind.
现在你少喝了四杯
Now you're four shots behind.
你最好把下一杯给我，要不杀了你
You better give me,the next one or I'll kill you.
豪斯...
House...
我在等检验结果，我...
[House laughing]
我只是在等待,等待检测结果,我是……
I was just waiting,for test results, I was...
现在有点忙，正在喝酒
Little busy right now.Getting my drink on.
不敢相信
Unbelievable.
那是我10年来看到最好的妞
Oof. That's the finest piece,I seen in ten years.
我该上了她
I could've hit that.
你没有
And you didn't.
嗯
Eh.
那你该是被关起来的
Then you're the one,that should be locked up.
告诉我，我一直想知道
Tell me something,I've been trying to figure this out.
为什么一个...
Why does a guy...
死囚，忽然想轻生?
...who's on Death Row,suddenly try to off himself?
你知道你的把戏
You know, you drank that copier fluid.
并不真的象玩手腕上的,小刀那样迷惑人
It's not as visually dramatic,as slitting your wrists,with a homemade shiv,
但还是可以骗人的
but it'll do the trick.
最初真的把我迷惑了
It just hit me all of a sudden.
就象，他们告诉我们什么时候吃,什么时候睡，什么时候走，所有的
It was like, they tell me,when to eat, when to sleep,when to walk, when to talk, everything.
我得能控制点什么，对吧?
I had to take control,of something, right?
什么时候你死
When you die,
我猜那就足够好了
I figured that was,as good as anything.
那个想法就这么冒出来了,就那么简单
And that thought just came to you.Just like that.
老兄，我告诉你，,23个小时...
Man, I told you.Twenty-three hours a...
嗯，你看，这是好消息
Mmm. Well, look.Here's the good news.
你喝的东西含90%甲醇,
The copier fluid you drank,contains about 90% methanol,
毒性很大，你喝的足够自杀
which is very poisonous,and you took more than,enough to kill yourself.
坏消息是，你刚才喝的酒
The bad news is,the alcohol you drank
含等量乙醇，将汇合你身体里的蚁酸
contains so much ethanol,that it's gonna bind with that,nasty formic acid raging through your body,
然后你会尿出来，无害
and you're just gonna,pee it out. Harmlessly.
老兄，你喝多了
Man, you are drunk.
是的，我还救了你的命
Yes, I am. I also saved your life.
哈，至少现在是的
Ha! At least for now.
早安
Morning!
你头疼吗?
Your head hurt?
不疼，是你的声音刺耳
No, you just have,a very grating voice.
你一直体重较轻
You always were a light weight.
你干嘛跟我说话?
Why are you talking to me?
我想让你痛苦这个原因可以吗?
Can't it be enough that,I want to cause you pain?
病人好了，你打算把他送回去?
The patient's okay now,you're going to send him back?
完全对
Absolutely.
我能信任你吗?
Can I trust you?
过去你是的
You used to.
我还是觉得病人有问题，我要留下他
I still think the patient's sick. I'm keeping him here.
现在要么你做你的事稳住医院
Now, either you can do your job,and keep the hospital informed, or
或者是你帮我确保医院不知情,替我争取时间
you can help me make sure,the hospital is not informed,and buy me some time.
试过CT吗?
Chase:,Have you done a CT?
试过?
Yeah, I have?
对照过吗?
Does it have contrast?
该做的她都做了,就差告诉病人她要死了
She's done everything she needs to do,except tell her patient that she's dying.
我告诉过你，只有我可以使用记号笔
I told you, only I get to,play with markers.
我们的犯人有了新症状
Our prisoner has a new symptom.
确诊前我不会告诉辛蒂她要死了
I'm not telling Cindy that she's dying,until the diagnosis is confirmed.
而我不相信克拉伦,以自杀控制自己的生命
I am not buying that,CLARENCE is trying to,take control of his life by suicide.
健康的人不自杀
Healthy people don't kill themselves.
健康的人也不杀别人
Healthy people don't kill other people.
这家伙刚被一个30年没判死刑的州,驳回了上诉请求
Guy just filed an appeal,in a state that hasn't actually,killed anybody in about 30 years.
如果不是自杀呢?如果是个逃跑计划呢?
What if it wasn't suicide?What if it was an escape plan?
喝足量甲醇运往医院,再从这逃走?
Drink enough methanol to,get transferred to a hospital,try to escape from here?
出色，能解释所有的事,只是他是被症状逼到了这里
Excellent. Explains everything,except the symptom that got him here.
他的心脏在他喝假酒前就发疯了
His heart went nuts,before he got stuck in that storage cell,and chugged a toner martini.
我觉得他的头脑出问题了
I think there's something,going on in his head.
检查颅内损伤，脑部感染,免疫系统疾病，做CT,LP，全套检查
Check for intracranial lesions,brain infections, autoimmune diseases...do a CT, LP, full workup.
州政府付钱，我们来狂欢吧
State's paying, so go nuts.
你哪来的这个疤痕?
Where'd you get these scars?
第一个月进来时被刺的,其后我保全了我的屁眼
I got shived my first month in.After I healed up I got my ass.
你们还觉得我有病吗?
You guys still think I'm sick?
没错
Obviously.
你干嘛在意?干嘛不就让我死算了?
Why you care?Why don't you just let me die?
我跟你不同
I'm different than you.
对，你象爱妈妈一样的爱我
Right, you love me,like your own mama.
那就是护士说我心脏快停时,你把她踢出去了
That's why the nurse says,you kicked her out,when my heart nearly stopped.
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
家族有精神病史吗?
Any family history,of mental illness?
我一直听说我爸是疯子，,从没看见过他和妈妈，是药吗？
I always heard my pa was crazy;,I never met the man with,my mom, it was the drugs.
有兄弟姐妹吗?
Any siblings?
我有弟弟，几乎是我带大的
I got a brother,pretty much raised him on my own.
不错的故事
Inspirational story.
- 他也在苦窑里熬时间吗?- 嘿
- He doin' time, too?- Hey.
他是好孩子，别随便评价你不知道的事
He's a good kid.Don't go judgin' what you don't know.
他的健康如何?
How's his health?
我进去后就没听过他的消息
I haven't heard from him,since I went inside.
跟他一起16年，给他换该死的尿布
Spent 16 years with him,changed his damn diapers.
你能想像你的一生都随坏事而去吗?
Can you imagine your whole life,bein' about the worst thing you ever did?
你杀了四个人
You killed four people.
不知何故，做乳酪面包失去了意义
Somehow, making mac and cheese,just the way he want kind of,loses its significance.
哦，不，你现在把,整个身体都扔我椅子上了
Oh no. Now you've left,your entire body in my chair.
这是你要什么的意思呢?
What does that mean you want?
我需要你平等的注意力
I need a segmental,bronchoalveolar lavage.
我把比对的CT结果带回来了
I take it the CT,with contrast came back.
- 不确定,- 活体切片会是的
- They're not definitive.- Biopsy would be.
活体切片会侵入病毒而且不必要
Biopsy would be,invasive and unnecessary.
但确定
And definitive.
但你不需要确诊，你想把错觉尽量持久
But you don't want definitive,you want to hang on to your,delusions as long as you can.
灌洗可以证明不是癌症
A lavage could prove,it's not cancer.
但你需要我的许可程序
But you need me,to approve the procedure.
尽管不够意思，但答案是不
Must be a bitch.The answer is no.
为什么？因为是我?
Why? Because it's me?
我跟你过劲了
I'm over you.
我跳上了花车，我恨你，好吗？
I've jumped on the bandwagon.I hate you, okay?
好，我们来治疗她吧
Great. Let's treat her.
什么啊?
What is it?
你不帮辛蒂，但却被这点尘土迷惑？
You won't help Cindy but you're,obsessed with this piece of dirt!
你难道是想证明别人不重要，,只有你的迷惑最重要？
Are you just trying to prove that,who someone is doesn't matter,that all that matters is your stupid puzzle?
好吧，同样治疗吧，一个测试,是我全部要求
Fine. Treat them the same.That's all I'm asking. One test.
哇，很出色
Wow, that is remarkable.
根据卖口香糖给小孩的人说,
According to those,patchouli-oli selling new-agers,
本该是晚期的病人
it's supposed to be,the terminal patient,
而你正经历死亡五步骤
but you're going,through the five stages.
你正顺滑地从愤怒过渡到讨价还价
You just made a completely,seamless transition,from anger to bargaining.
再完成两小时出诊,你可以得到一个程序
Cover two more of my clinic hours,you can have your one procedure.
没损伤，没动脉瘤
No lesions, no aneurysms.
很讽刺，但一个杀人犯的头脑,看上去挺正常的
Ironically, the mind of a killer,looks completely normal.
如果有人让你描述我
If someone asks you,to describe me to them,
你第一告诉他们什么?
what's the first thing,you'd tell them?
不可靠,你问什么?
Insecure.What are you asking?
就象，你跟我初次约会？
Like, if you were setting me up,on a blind date.
你会象个姑娘介绍我，黑人,神经学医生，偷车的?
Would you describe me,to the girl as the black guy,a neurologist, car thief?
那家伙触动你了吧?
This guy's really,getting to you, isn't he?
没有感染的迹象
There's no sign of infection.
得做活体切片了
You're gonna have to do the biopsy.
你的死囚还在这里
Cuddy:,Your Death Row guy's still here!
是，抱歉，得让他稳定
Yeah, sorry.Just gotta get him stabilized.
再留他几个小时就可以走了
Probably keep him on fluids,for a few more hours, then off he goes.
哦，是吗？,我以为你还认为他有病呢
Oh yeah? 'Cause I'm figuring,that you still think he's sick.
猜测需要推理,我猜测你没猜对
Figuring requires deductive reasoning.I'm figuring that you did no figuring.
史戴西出卖了我，对吧?
Stacy just ratted me out, right?
再不能有律师和当事人之间的信任了
So much for attorney-client privledge.
我是当事人，你个白痴,史戴西对这家医院负有责任
I'm the client, you moron.Stacy has a duty to this hospital.
- 对,- 我要把他送会监狱去
- Right.- I'm sending him back to prison.
哇 ，不行，法庭令
Whoa, can't. Court order.
法庭令说他得被公告健康
Court order says he has to,be declared healthy.
没指出由哪个医生公告
Doesn't specify what doctor needs,to make that declaration.
- 怎么了，克拉伦?- 我的肠子
- What is it, Clarence?- My gut!
你是否可以描述一下？,是刺痛还是跳着疼
Would you describe it,as a shooting pain?A throbbing pain?
还是因为你不想回监狱而假疼?
Or maybe an imaginary pain,because you don't want to,go back to prison?
哪里疼?
Where does it hurt?
我的肠子，我觉得我被刺中了
My gut, I feel like,I'm getting stabbed!
他该知道，让我看看
[Screams again]
嗯,他会知道。,让我看一看
Well, he'd know.Let me take a look.
哦，也就是说除了一个罪犯,所有人都说谎
Oh, so everybody lies,except a convicted murderer.
我不觉得他是装的，你呢医生?
I don't think he's faking this stuff.What do you think, Doctor?
[克拉伦斯尖叫,更多的强调]
[Clarence screams,a lot more for emphasis.]
我没选择
I didn't have any choice.
不，你得告诉卡蒂
No, you had to tell Cuddy.
她是你老板，我明白了
She's your boss, I get it.
希特勒也觉得他是造福全人类呢
Hitler thought he was,doing the world a favor, too.
对，跟那个水平差不多
Yeah, pretty much,on that same level.
甘地没因朋友要求就做海洋漫步
Gandhi didn't march the sea,because his buddies asked him too,
泡泡没把所有老师消灭因为他需要朋友
Pol Pot didn't wipe out the teachers,because he wanted to make friends.
你现在不是在交朋友
You're not making,friends right now.
我信任了你
I trusted you.
我知道
I know.
韦森是傻瓜，我是白痴
Wilson's a fool.I'm an idiot.
我得做我认为对的事
I had to do,what I thought was right.
那是每个人行事的准则
It's the only reason,anyone does anything.
外科手术进展顺利,他们切除了近一尺的坏死肠子
The surgery went fine.They removed almost,a foot of necrotic bowel.
他们给他上了手铐送去康复了
They're shackling him,and taking him to recovery.
我好奇
I wonder.
我好奇为什么克拉伦杀了第二个狱友
I wonder why Clarence,killed that second inmate.
好吧，我来接,你说什么呢?
Fine, I'll bite.What the hell are you talking about?
凡事皆有目的
Everything we do,is dictated by motive.
他干嘛杀他女友?
Why did he kill his girlfriend?
因为他是疯子
Because he's a maniac!
那是他给的原因么?
Is that the reason he gave?
她骗他
She was cheating on him.
嫉妒
Jealousy.
那使他进监狱,杀了第一号狱友，为什么?
That gets him sent to prison,where he kills inmate number one. Why?
那家伙先袭击他
Guy attacked him first.
复仇,其后杀了谁?
Revenge.Who'd he killed after that?
狱警
Prison guard.
他的档案满是虐待投诉
Got a file full of abuse complaints.
估计虐待克拉伦好几个月了
Probably been kicking,Clarence's ass for months.
克拉伦是为民除害呢
Clarence is just ridding,the world of bad seeds.
管它叫'报偿'.
Call that one ''retribution''.
然后杀了二号狱友
Then he kills inmate number two.
有人知道原因么?
Anybody know why?
没，里面没有
Nuh-uh. It's not in there.
我突然需要一个理由了吗?
All of a sudden,I got to have a reason?
那样不规则，医生热爱不规则
It's an anomaly.Doctors love anomalies.
x光有黑点，MRI有亮点……
Dark spot on an x-ray,bright spot on an MRI....
杀第二个狱友相当于,谋杀案中的尿里有血
Killing that second inmate,is the homicidal equivalent,of blood in the urine.
不恰当
It doesn't fit.
我对不恰当很感兴趣
I'm interested in,things that don't fit.
告诉我你做的理由
Tell me why you did it.
一个你吹嘘的受害者
Your other victims,you were almost bragging about.
这家伙有什么不同?
What was different,about this guy?
发生在我在gen-pop的时候
It happened,when I was in gen-pop.
我在图书馆，看书
I was in the library, just readin',
我开始觉得很紧张
and I started feelin' real nervous.
这家伙盯着我，我可以感觉到他的眼睛
This guy was staring at me,I could feel his eyes.
象在我脖子上挖洞一样,让我发疯
Digging holes in the back of my neck,made me feel crazy.
我脸上汗如雨下
Sweat was pouring,down my face.
我能听到心跳声进入我的耳朵
I could hear my heartbeat,racing in my ears.
我朝着他发狂了
I just raged out on the dude.
那么发狂如何细分?
So what's the differential for raging out?
睾丸激素过剩，类固醇……
Excess testosterone, steroids...
刺激...
Adrenaline...
准备给克拉伦做手术
Prep Clarence for surgery.
跟大家分享吧
Care to share with the class.
哦，拜托，我还得给你拼写出来吗？,嗜铬神经细胞瘤
Oh, come on.Do I have to spell it out for you?Pheochromocytoma.
其实，我不知道怎么拼
Actually, I'm not sure how you spell it.
可你自己说的，刺激
But you said it yourself, adrenaline.
嗜铬神经细胞瘤位于肾上腺管壁,随意释放大量物质
Pheochomocytoma sits,on top of the adrenal gland,randomly spits out oodles of the stuff.
精彩，解释很多事
It's perfect, it explains everything.
心动过速，肺水肿,血管收缩导致肠坏死
The tachycardia, pulmonary edema,the vasoconstriction that cause,the necrotic bowel...[Elevator dings]
甚至可以解释他扯烂床围栏的蛮力
Even explains how he had,the strength to rip the rail off his bed.
但该症异常罕见
But pheo's extremely rare.
我喜欢罕见，准备MRI，卡麦伦在哪里？
I love rare. Set up an MRI.Where's Cameron?
就象我不知道似的
Like I don't know.
卡梅隆博士吗?我能借你请教吗?
Dr. Cameron?Could I borrow you for a consult?
甘苦滋味是肿瘤科的头等大事,我已获得所有活体切片结果了
Bittersweet thing about being,head of the oncology department,I get CCed in all the biopsy results.
对，我知道，她是晚期
Yeah, I know.She's terminal.
对，那么我就当你是在通知她呢?
Yeah. So I take it you were,in there informing her?
嗯，我还没那么做，我正...
Well, I...I hadn't exactly,gotten around to that, but I was just...
干嘛?交朋友吗?
Doing what?Making friends?
辛蒂离婚了，没孩子,没胞亲，父母双亡
Cindy's divorced.She doesn't have any kids,no siblings, both her parents are gone...
做她朋友不是你的工作
It's not your job,to be her friend.
你懂吗?那不值
Do you understand?And it's not worth it.
她最后的几天觉得好，而你,会难受好几年
She feels better her few final days,and you're not the same, maybe for years.
你觉得不值
You don't think it's worth it.
我知道不值
I know it's not worth it.
我丈夫...
My husband w...
我是在他被诊断为晚期癌症后遇到他的
I met him just after he was,diagnosed with terminal brain cancer.
如果我没跟他结婚
If I hadn't married him,
他会孤独
he was alone.
当一个好人死的时候,该对世界有些影响
When a good person dies,there should be an impact on the world.
有人该注意到，有人该难过
Somebody should notice.Somebody should be upset.
嗜什么?
Pheo what?
我都不记得了
I don't even remember.
是个卖弄地描述小瘤子的说法
It's just a fancy way of saying,small, adrenaline-secreting tumor.
对，这该说清楚了
Yeah, that clarified it for you.
你需要知道的就是如果我对了,我们可以解决了它
All you need to know is,if I'm right, we can fix it.
需要找到它,要做核磁共振
Just need to find it.We need an MRI.
对大部分人来说毫无痛苦
It's completely painless for most people.
对我来说不是?
But not for me?
我猜你是在监狱里做的这些纹身？
I assume you got,those tattoos in prison.
监狱纹身用的自制墨水含重金属
Prison tats often contain,inks with heavy metals.
核磁共振基本上是一块大型磁铁
The MRI's basically a giant magnet.
它会把那些重金属,从你的皮肤里吸出来
It'd suck those metallic inks,right out of your skin.
别动，要不还得再做
Stop squirming.Don't make us do this again.
大婴儿
Big baby.
还是看不到什么啊
Still don't see anything.
关掉
Clarence: ,Turn it off!
有个Waldo
There's Waldo.
找到了，克拉伦
Found it, Clarence.
关掉，把这该死的东西关掉
Clarence:,Turn it off! Turn this damn thing off!
把他关在里面直到你们找到为止
Keep him in there,until you guys see it too.
狗日的
Son of a bitch.
看来他们把瘤子顺利拿出来了
Looks like they got,the pheo out successfully.
那么现在呢?
So what now?
克拉伦要会死牢了
Clarence goes back to Death Row.
就这样?
Just like that?
他治好了
He's cured.
肿瘤导致他难以抑制怒气,很明显直接导致他的最初谋杀
That tumor caused random shots of adrenaline,which obviously led to the rage attacks that,made him a murderer in the first place.
以上帝之名，你对了
By God, you're right!
我们得找外科医生留着那个瘤子
Let's call the surgeons,we've got to save that tumor.
把它安置上证人席
Put it on the witness stand.
我们可以为克拉伦的上诉作证
We could testify,at Clarence's appeal.
你闻得见吗?
[sniffs] You smell that?
我觉得那是伪善的臭气
I think that is the stink of hypocrisy.
你没考虑,克拉伦的社会环境对他负有责任
You wouldn't even consider the notion,that Clarence's social upbringing was,responsible for what he became,
而你却要作证,把一切都归咎于一个小肿瘤
but now you're sprinting to,the witness stand to blame,everything on a little tumor.
一个人的环境和,他的生物性是完全不同的
A person's upbringing and their biology,are completely different.
是，你只战胜了一个
Yeah. See, you only,overcame one of them.
嗯，我们就算给克拉伦一个通行证吧?
Well, let's just give,Clarence a free pass, hmmm?
你会因此得罪所有该病症的患者
Course, you're probably going to,piss off all those other pheo sufferers
因为他们在努力克制自己的怒气而,成为律师,赛车手,甚至是医生
who managed to control,their rage attacks and become lawyers,race car doctors, and even doctors.
切除肿瘤可以中止胡乱杀人,却不能给他免罪
Removing that tumor puts a stop,to those random shots adrenaline,but doesn't absolve him.
你希望他被处决吗?
You want him to be executed?
我不是那么说的
That's not what I'm saying.
有意见吗？
Got an opinion?
每个人都有意见
Everyone's got an opinion.
我，我想我会在克拉伦的上诉中作证
I, uh, I think I'm gonna testify,at Clarence's appeal.
你可以做你认为对的事
You'll do what you think is right.
我只是咳嗽而已
But it's just a cough.